First I am going to show you what to do with our saturated book.
As I mentioned before how we deal with each book follows from saturated to least saturated going in a very prescribed set of steps.
The important thing to remember for the saturated book is that you want to keep it up on end while you are letting it dry.
This is to allow the maximum amount of air flow to the pages.
You can see that the pages are too wet in order to separate even, so you want to be able to get as much air flowing around here through the top as possible.
If your book is so wet that it doesn't want to stand up on end then go ahead and use book holders, bookends in order to keep it upright.
You want to make sure that the bookends that you use don't have anything on the edge that is going to get wet and rub off on the book or stick to the book and damage it even more.
It's important for you to have something absorbent underneath the book.
You want to have paper towels or some type of absorbent cloth.
It's important because it is going to get wet and you are going to want to keep an eye on your book and check it at least every half hour in order to change the material underneath it and to flip the book around.